so I thought we should be out here in
the forest in the beautiful nature of
Sweden and record a dull b-roll sequence
using nothing but my smartphone
[Music]
so most of you that are watching this
probably do have a smartphone or
something like the Samsung Galaxy s8 or
as 10 like I do this can shoot in Full
HD in 240 frames per second which is
kind of cool so it's gonna give us that
like b-roll look with kind of a steady
steady camera because you can like slow
that down and add some stabilization in
Final Cut Pro but I thought I'd show you
the whole process of shooting a be wrong
with the phone here in the forest so
usually what I do is that I try to find
some kind of details that is going to be
interesting for the b-roll sequence to
have as I am looking around in the
forest and when I'm looking around we
can see the stump
here this is kind of kind of interesting
it looks kind of kind of like worn out
with this part here and the moss on top
so this this was gonna include and if we
keep looking we can also see that
there's this super tiny waterfall here
that like super small River
it looks really and first thing that is
also something that we can include we
can also include some of the barks here
on the trees and hopefully just
hopefully the Sun is going to come
through the trees right here somewhere
and then we could get the Sun flare
coming out from that as well but those
are a couple of things that I think of
like straight up that we can include in
the b-roll sequence so let's get to
shooting the actual b-roll sequence
alright let's let's open up the camera
up here and in the camera you want to
make sure that you have it is set to you
slow motion and then basically just tap
where you want the focus to be and then
keep recording let's start with a stump
a oh my legs I feel like an old man
hmm okay I'm gonna have to rethink this
basically like moving back and forth a
lot of times to make sure that I get the
shot so just move the camera back and
forth and try to keep it as steady as
you can try to move like close to the
ground that actually looks really really
good so let's move on to the next thing
we're gonna try to get details shot off
of these channel like stumps three
stumps what do you call these is this
like three this is not branches or is
like cut down branches whoa what is it
what do you call these I don't know but
yeah these things we're gonna call it
things I'm gonna try to get shot of
these because this these can be
interesting you know to get that forest
feeling when you're hanging a cellphone
you don't want to do too much movements
in your shots because that is not gonna
look good because it's gonna look way
too shaky so try to hold your camera
like this with four fingers and then
basically just move and try to pan at
the same time as you're moving you can
also do like some tilting if you want to
do that because that is probably gonna
look good as well but I feel kind of
satisfied with that so let's try to get
the the smaller river here as well let's
see if we can't get as close to the
water as possible when we're getting
this shot yeah I'm feeling like the seal
on the beach I really hope that I do get
some good footage of this
[Music]
all right love you shot I'm down
I'm also gonna get a shot of the camera
like panning around like this because
that is a really cool shot especially
when it comes to like forests because it
feels immersive okay that looked great
so now we're gonna get a sequence of me
looking up towards the trees so we get
that like natural progression to the
shot that we got up towards the trees I
think that looks good
look at that that oh oh oh as the money
shot right there the absolute last shot
that I won't have is me walking out of
the forest to make like the whole b-roll
sequence feel like it's coming to an end
this looks really really good so I'm
just gonna put the camera right here and
then I'm gonna walk towards that and
we're done okay let's go back to the
office and edit alright back to the
office
feels great there you know I know why
I'm speaking Irish I don't know let's
open up all the footage in Final Cut Pro
and I'll show you how I edited that
sequence together okay so the first clip
that we are going to use is gonna be the
one off the tree stump here so we're
gonna drag this to the timeline and
we're gonna like when we are starting to
pan we're gonna cut it so we press B for
the blade tool then we ain't select
backspace delete that we don't want to
have that and then we want to slow this
clip down because we shot everything in
120 frames per second as you remember
and then we're gonna mark this and then
we'll choose custom and 20 percent so
now that it would play it back you can
see that looks really good it looks kind
of steady as well so I don't know if we
gonna add some stabilization to this but
the clip doesn't have to be longer than
maybe like 2 or 3 seconds so we gonna
cut the clip at 3 seconds to begin with
I think so when it's the beef or the
blade tool and then we're gonna cut it
you're gonna mark the rest of the clip
and hit backspace the second clip that
we're going to use is gonna be where I
look around
the forest basically and you had the Sun
coming in the back and looks really
really good so you know drag this to the
timeline like that and the phone didn't
really rotate so we're gonna have to do
that by ourselves and we're gonna mark
the clip we're gonna go up here to the
transform and then we're gonna choose
the rotation and his minus 90 and then
we're gonna make the clip bigger so
we're gonna drag it up on the scale to
180 and then we want to slow the clip
down so we're gonna slow choose custom
and 20% this is not gonna be longer than
like two or three seconds so we're gonna
cut it as six seconds like that maybe we
can take the next clip is gonna be when
like we pen on the trees I think that is
gonna fit good into here so I'm gonna
choose that one the same thing here we
want to slow this down mark this which
you want to choose custom again 20
percent I think you know by now so I
don't have saved and then we can add a
speed ramp here so shift be at the
playhead and then go forward some rock
here shift B and we're gonna choose fast
times 8 so perfect perfect and now I
wanna have a clip of the water so we're
gonna choose this that is a good
sequence so we're gonna choose this one
and we're gonna drag it to the timeline
slowing this down so we're gonna go back
to the beginning and then we're going to
include the clip off the tree bar to
that I shot as well I'm going to drag
this just after the first clip that we
got and slow this down as well okay
let's do a speed ramp here shift B and
then move forward to some run here just
so that we can see the Sun
we have my face looks good as the forest
up spinning around the water and then we
can finish this sequence off by me
walking away into the forest right and
since all the clips have some kind of
motion in them the last cut feels a
little bit out of place but we're gonna
add some fake motion to it so that it
feels more dynamic so what you want to
do is go up to the transform tab and
then you want to go in just a little bit
till I say a hundred and twenty and then
we're gonna drag the position X to the
right to minus 185 then we want to set a
keyframe so that when we move forward to
some around here you want to set this to
zero and we can play that back to see
how it looks nice dynamic motion going
on here
in the last clip - and of course we're
gonna add the anamorphic bars so let's
do that by choosing the generators and
then choose custom we're gonna drag this
to the timeline and it's extended all
the way that our clip is playing and
then we're gonna choose crop top crop
top 960 and then we're gonna hold alt
drag this out and then we're gonna reset
the top one like that and then go to the
bottom one and type 960 there as well
and now we got ourselves a really cool
b-roll sequence that is shot entirely on
a smartphone that looks like this
[Music]
every note that you enjoyed this video
because this video is something that I
planned on shooting a long time but I
actually thought it was gonna be way
harder than it was because shooting that
b-roll was really really simple actually
and you know I really hope that you feel
more confident in taking your cell phone
go out shoot some great content create
some dope be roles with that because I
mean come on this camera that you always
carry with you right thank you so much
for watching if you like the video do
give it a thumbs up because it does make
a huge difference if you haven't
subscribed yet that would be really
appreciated as well if there is any kind
of camera gear that you want to buy I
would appreciate if you bought it
through the affiliate links below
because that helps support me and this
channel to create even better content
and it doesn't cost you anything extra
so thanks for that as well until next
time take care
as boss I wonder if I can do a couple of
American excellency the only accent that
I really know in the USA is busily this
one and I don't know what if this is an
accent I don't know
but and you know this was always Presley
accent and I guess y'all can speak and I
guess your own can speak and take some
right is that an accent I think that is
an action of the United States of
America I don't know is it